Guide to the Eduardo Quevedo Papers, 1929-1968
Department of Special Collections
Eduardo Quevedo Papers,
1929-1968
Special Collections M0349
Quevedo, Eduardo, 1929-1968.
9 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Edward T. Quevedo, 1981.
Biographical Note
Eduardo Quevedo, a leading political figure in the Mexican-American community in Los Angeles, was a veteran of efforts to mobilize California's Mexican-American voters. Politically active for over thirty years, Quevedo was a candidate in the 1940 race for assemblyman in California's 52nd District and in 1942 in the 40th District. Although unsuccessful in these campaigns, he continued to work to make the Mexican-American community a major political force. He served as president of the Coordinating Council of Latin American Youth during and after the Zoot Suit Riot of 1943 and was appointed by Governor Edmund G. Brown to the Department of Employment's state advisory council. One of the organizers of the Mexican-American Political Association (MAPA), he went on to become its president during 1965-1966.
Scope and Content Note
The personal papers of Eduardo Quevedo include correspondence, leaflets, photographs and reports covering the years 1929-1968. The correspondence files from the 1940s, included in Series I (Personal Files), document his role in several early Mexican-American political organizations. There is a large oversized scrapbook in Series I, (stored in Box 21), that contains clippings and memorabilia that commemorate Quevedo's long and distinguished career. Series IV on KMEX, the Mexican-American Station in Los Angeles, contains information about the programing for the Spanish speaking community in Los Angeles. Series V is a long series of correspondence from the Mexican American Political Association (MAPA), (1963-1966). Series VI contains the general file from the MAPA office, arranged in alphabetical order by folder title. The Manpower Opportunities Project (MOP), Series VII, also a long file, contains minutes, project reports, and financial records. Series VIII is a file of Activity Reports from the MOP field workers arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the field worker. There is a small collection of photographs (Series IX) that show Quevedo with prominent political figures, and in the last series, a few issues of Mexican-American newspapers and clippings.
Container List
- SERIES I: PERSONAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION, 1929-1967
  - Resume, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eduardo Quevedo, 1903-1964, a biographical presentation, by the Southern California Spanish-Speaking Committee to Honor Eduardo Quevedo, leather bound manuscript, March 8, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eduardo Quevedo, 1903-1964,additional copies of text, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guest Book, with signatures, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of Recognition from the Mexican-American community, September 9, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Last Official Message by Eduardo Quevedo, President of MAPA, To Convention Delegates, Riverside, California, July 13-15, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Death Takes Latin Leader Quevedo Here, clipping, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, in-coming, Congress of Mexican and Hispanic Americans, and Federation of Spanish American Voters, 1939-1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1947, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Law suit, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Employee Service Letter for Melchor Quevedo, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Telegram from Governor Olson, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mortgage Statement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook of Clippings and Memorabilia, 1939 - (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Xerox of scrapbook pages (Box 21, Folder 2)
- SERIES II: GOVERNOR'S ADVISORY COUNCIL TO THE DEPARTMENT OF EMPLOYMENT, 1965-1966
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- SERIES III: POLITICAL CAMPAIGNS, 1944-1966
  - Brown, Pat, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Senator Dennis Chavez Rally, speeches and financial records, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Political Endorsements, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Quevedo for State Assembly, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Quevedo, Hank, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Viva Kennedy Clubs, directory, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yorty, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- SERIES IV: KMEX TELEVISION STATION, 1963-1968
  - KMEX, Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - KMEX, Correspondence, June-August 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - KMEX, Correspondence, September, October, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - KMEX, Correspondence, September, October 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - KMEX, Correspondence, October 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - KMEX letters from viewers, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - KMEX letters from viewers, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Market Survey for KMEX-TV Channel 34, The Spanish International Broadcasting Corporation, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Press releases, ca. 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speak Out on Education, Broadcast, December 12, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- SERIES V: MAPA (MEXICAN-AMERICAN POLITICAL ASSOCIATION), 1963-1966
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re: Crystal City, Texas election, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re: Dinner Dance for labor leaders, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence re: Fourth Annual Convention, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with the University of California at Los Angeles, and the University of Southern California, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with the U.S. Department of Labor, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with the U.S. Department of Labor, (continued) 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- SERIES VI: MAPA, GENERAL FILES, 1964-1967
  - Advisory Committee, 1966 -Automation (Box 4)
  - Braceros - Dinner Dance, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Economic and Youth Opportunity - An Evaluation of Mexican-American Studies, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Fair Employment - Johnson, Lyndon (Box 7)
  - Juvenile - Migrants (Box 8)
  - Migrant Ministry - Programs and Flyers (Box 9)
  - Proposition 17, 1964 -Tenants Council, Fresno (Box 10)
  - Tenneco, Inc. - War on Poverty Exibits (Box 11)
  - Water Projects - Zenovich (Box 12)
- SERIES VII: MANPOWER OPPORTUNITIES PROJECT, 1966-1967
  - Minutes of Staff meetings, Los Angeles, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of Staff meetings, Fresno, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Project Activities Report, March-June 30, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Project Activities Report, period ending November 30, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Project Activities Report, December 15, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Project Activities Report, period ending February 15, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Southern Area Office Monthly Reports, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Manpower Opportunities Final Report, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with the Department of Employment, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Robert Martinez, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - General Files, Advisory Committee, 1966 -Conferences on Training, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 10-12)
  - General Files, Forms - Paid Invoices, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1-22)
  - General Files, Paid Invoices, 1967 -Vouchers, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1-33)
- SERIES VIII: MANPOWER OPPORTUNITIES PROJECT, FIELD REPORTS, 1966-1967
  - Airozo - Gonzales (Box 16, Folder 1-10)
  - Gonzales - Mendez (Box 17, Folder 1-11)
  - Mendez - Sapien (Box 18, Folder 1-14)
  - Talancon - Ybarra (Box 19, Folder 1-7)
- SERIES IX: PHOTOGRAPHS, 1960s
  - Gonzales, Eugene, Assistant to the State Superintendent of Public Instrtuction, n.d and Max Rafferty and Gonzales, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Quevedo, Governor Nelson Rockefeller, and a third unidentified man on set at KMEX-TV channel 34, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Quevedo with various political figures, ca. 1964? (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Quevedo and family, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Quevedo with Robert Kennedy, n.sd (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Quevedo at Yorty rally, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Quevedo, at the podium, Pat Brown rally, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Quevedo at Younger Rally, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Quevedo, and others, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Quevedo (at banquet in his honor?), (3) proofs, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Stockton homeless, jobless, single men, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 19)
- SERIES X: CLIPPINGS, ca. 1959-1967
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 20, Folder 1)
- SERIES XI: NEWSPAPERS, 1963-1966
  - The Voice of the Spanish Speaking People (MAPA), 1965-66 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - West, September 18, 25, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - La Opinion, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Tribuna Obrera, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Vida, news of the Mexican American, November 13, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook storage box (Box 21)